atcc.org 2016-06-09

# Privacy Policy

### Last Updated April 2, 2008

This Privacy Policy describes the privacy practices of the American Type Culture Collection ("ATCC®", "we", "us", or "our") and our use of information. This Privacy Policy describes how we use the personally identifiable information that you provide to us offline (e.g., through postal mail or fax) or online (e.g., through our website located at [www.atcc.org](http://www.atcc.org/) (the "Site")). The term "personally identifiable information" as used in this Privacy Policy includes your full name, e-mail address, mailing address, telephone number, or credit card information.

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy. If we make changes that affect the way we collect or use your personally identifiable information, these changes and their effective date will be posted in this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the Site after we post a revised Privacy Policy means you have accepted the Privacy Policy. If we materially change our practices for the collection or use of your personally identifiable information, your personally identifiable information will be governed by the Policy under which it was originally collected unless you have been provided notice of, and have had an opportunity to object to, the change.

Terms of Use for the Site accompany this Privacy Policy. Please review these terms.

ATCC is a wholly owned, non-profit subsidiary of International Bioresources Groupä ("IBG"), a non-profit, 501(c)(3) corporation. We are not a government agency.

When you use the online shopping cart, place orders, submit account applications or other forms, use the "contact us" page, e-mail us, establish a Web user profile, submit a résumé, and at other times, you may provide ATCC with your personally identifiable information. If you place an order, we may collect credit card or other payment information. We may also collect personally identifiable information and other information when you apply for and use our custom services such as testing and Patent and Safe Deposit services, 

In order to help process your orders and to protect against potential fraud, we may verify with third parties the personally identifiable information you provide to us. In the course of such verification, we may receive personally identifiable information about you from such third parties and combine it with the information you provide directly to us.

ATCC’s Web servers may automatically collect non-personally identifiable information such as website usage information when you visit the Site, including: the number and frequency of visits to each web page; your Internet Protocol address; your browser and platform type; your length of stay; the website from which you entered; and the actions you take.

Cookies are small bits of information that a website places on the hard drive of your computer. Certain pages of the Site may use session and/or persistent cookies to track and store your personally identifiable information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, and to allow us to recognize you if you return to the Site using the same computer and browser.

You can program your computer to warn you each time a cookie is being sent or to refuse cookies completely. However, without cookies you may not have access to certain features on our Site. For example, you will not be able to place or track orders.

We may use your personally identifiable information alone, or when aggregated with other information, for a variety of purposes as described below:

  * Account Set-Up and Service
  * Communications about Products and Services
  * Site Improvement
  * Enforcement of ATCC Policies
  * Compliance with Regulatory Requirements and Applicable Laws
  * Compliance with Our Obligations as a Government Contractor
  * Customer Notifications
  * Other Purposes, as disclosed at the time the information is collected
  * Notwithstanding the forgoing uses, résumé information will be used only to evaluate your candidacy for a job opening.

We may combine the personally identifiable information you provide to ATCC with other information about you that is available to us, including non-personally identifiable information and information from third parties.

We may share the personally identifiable information we collect with other IBG affiliates for the purposes described in the "How We Use the Information Collected" section of this Privacy Policy  We may also share your information with our third party service providers (including contractors and distributors) to validate your payment information, to prevent fraud, to fulfill your order, and to perform other activities related to sales of ATCC products and services. We may share personally identifiable information of individuals submitting résumés or making inquiries concerning employment with other IBG affiliates and third party service providers for the purpose of conducting employment evaluation. Third party service providers to whom we supply your personally identifiable information may use this information only to provide ATCC with a specific service and not for any other purpose. ATCC does not make its customer lists available for sale to third parties.

In addition, ATCC may disclose personally identifiable information or other information to law enforcement, regulatory agencies, other government officials or other third parties, as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate: a) in connection with an investigation of fraud or other activity that is illegal or may expose us to legal liability; b) to enforce our policies governing our Site; and c) for regulatory compliance. We may also disclose such information in connection with any merger or consolidation with, or sale of substantially all of our assets to, a third party, provided that such third party agrees to comply with our Privacy Policy.

Materials deposited with us or purchased from us through our patent depository services are subject to special disclosure requirements. For individuals depositing material with us under our patent depository services, information related to such a deposit remains restricted until the issuance of the pertinent U.S. patent. Once a patent has been issued for the material included in the deposit, we are required to make the material that is the subject of the patent available to the public and may be required to supply certain personally identifiable information about the depositor to the public. For individuals purchasing material that was deposited as a patent deposit, we are required to share certain personally identifiable information about the purchaser with the depositor.

Certain other materials deposited with us are subject to special disclosure requirements established by the depositor. For individuals purchasing material deposited with us for resale that is subject to such disclosure requirements, we may be required to share your personally identifiable information with the depositor. If such requirements exist for a particular deposit, you will be notified of these terms and will be asked to agree to them before your order is fulfilled.

ATCC makes commercially reasonable efforts to use industry-standard security technologies to secure your information, including personally identifiable information. Servers where personally identifiable information is stored are password and firewall-protected, and access is limited to those employees and independent contractors with whom we have an agreement to keep the information confidential, who have a need to know, and who agree to access the information only for the purposes identified above. Financial information is transmitted and stored in encrypted form.

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, ATCC will not use the personally identifiable information you provide to us for purposes different from the purposes for which it was submitted. If you have consented to receive promotional or other e-mail communications from ATCC, we may periodically use your e-mail address to send such e-mail communications. If you want to stop receiving e-mail communications, you can click the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each promotional e-mail.

This Site may contain links to Internet sites operated by other parties. ATCC is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Internet sites. ATCC provides links to other Internet sites as a convenience to users. Access to any other Internet sites linked to this Site is at your own risk.

You may ask us to review and update the personally identifiable information you provide to us by contacting Customer Service or by making changes to your personally identifiable information on-line. We will take reasonable steps to correct personally identifiable information that you inform us is incorrect.

If you have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact the ATCC Webmaster using the Contact Us Form.
